

# Adam Matan

R&D Manager. Seeking a technical leadership role. Wix, Yahoo, Waze, Zoomin, Vioozer, Reshuffle

# What do I bring to the table?

Experienced R&D Manager with a track record of leading full stack groups with 15+ BE, mobile, and web developers. Owning execution and delivery, team building, and dev/management/product communication.

A cloud backend developer at heart (StackOverflow, Servefault, GIS), with extensive experience with the AWS, Docker, Python, and serverless ecosystems.

## Experience

### 2021-2022 Director / R&D Manager (Zoomin Software), Zoomin.

Zoomin is a leader in the documentation portal sector, with Fortune 500 customers. I am responsible for leading the next-gen group that reimplements the existing Haskell product on modern cloud platforms. My responsibilities include directly leading 15 developers, tech leads, product managers, and DevOps specialists. During my tenure, we completely rewrote the search engine, created a new data ingestion pipeline, built a robust CI/CD platform, and delivered an offline offering for our portal that enabled new markets for the product. The tech stack includes AWS, Python, Go, K8S/EKs, and Git(Ops).

#### 2019-2021 R&D Manager (Wix Code / Velo), wix.com.

Wix is a world leader in the DIY website market.

As an R&D manager, I was responsible for leading a group of developers building <u>Velo</u>, Wix's serverless platform that lets any developer build a production-grade webapp in minutes, with backend code, frontend code, cronjobs, logs, APIs, and a secret manager.

My responsibilities include directly leading 15 developers, team leaders, and product managers, planning and executing the engineering roadmap, communicating with other teams and external partners, and hiring.

#### 2017-2018 Head of DevRel and Developer, reshuffle.com (acquired by Twitter).

Reshuffle develops a low-latency Serverless Function-as-a-Service (FaaS) platform on public cloud platforms. As Head of DevRel, I developed open-source low-latency demo apps, wrote the company dev site, presented at <u>numerous international conferences</u>, and co-founded the <u>TLV Serverless meetup</u> with more than 500 members, and <u>Israel's first Serverless conference</u>.

#### 2014-2017 CTO, vioozer.com, Tel Aviv, Israel.

I led a team of 8 developers (Mobile, web, backend, and BI) that built a location-based product from scratch to a full production system with hundreds of thousands of concurrent users.

We built a cloud service that featured location-based questions and answers offered as an SDK to mobile apps. I designed and implemented the system using a microservice architecture on AWS/EC2/Nginx using Python/Flask, PostgreSQL/PostGIS, Redis, and S3.

#### 2012-2013 Java developer, Yahoo!, Ramat Gan, Israel.

Developed fast ad-matching technology in Yahoo's Creative Innovation Center team.

2009-2012 Infrastructure developer, Waze.com (acquired by Google), Raanana, Israel.

Algorithmic improvements of large databases, server maintenance, and system architecture design

## Education

2005-2009 B.Sc., Hebrew University, Jerusalem.

Major in Computer Science, Minor in the Amirim Humanities Honors program.

Parts of my final project, guided by Prof. Dror Feitelson, were published as an academic paper (Jbara, A., Matan, A. & Feitelson, D.G. <u>High-MCC Functions in the Linux Kernel.</u> Empir Software Eng 19, 1261–1298 (2014).)

## Community Activities

2016- Reversim Summit, Volunteering organizer.

Organized one of the <u>largest community conferences in Israel</u>, coordinating a team of 25 volunteers, 53 speakers and 1k attendees. Led the entire conference in 2016, the content team in 2017, and moderating since 2018.

2018 Serverless TLV, Founder and Organizer.

Organized Israel's first Serverless conference, <u>Serverless Days TLV</u>, an international developer conference with 220 attendees from Israel, Europe, and the US, along with an active meetup group.

## Public Speaking

2018- Public speaking in Israel and abroad.

I delivered numerous public speaking sessions, both as an independent speaker and as a DevRel. Conferences include Reversim, Serverless conferences, and FITC Web Unleashed. See the complete list with videos.

# Military service

2005-Present IDF Armored Corps Res. Major. Armored company leader

1999-2003 IDF Armored Corps tank platoon leader. Retired as a lieutenant.